Hello everyone, today we are going to learn how to use the selection grid tool to deal with the problem of clothes passing through the model.
Since we are going to use the selection grid tool, let's first learn about its basic knowledge.
Select the mouse and select the grid brush tool.
In the drop-down menu, you can see three selection grid tools that can be used.
The first is the selection grid brush.
Use this tool to press the mouse and left keys on the board and drag and drop to highlight the selected area.
There are various additional functions that can be used on the right key in the selected area.
For example, the selected part of the grid is divided into details and the selected area is converted into a fixed frame.
Or you can move it around or shape it.
Among them, the part of the grid is converted into a fixed frame and the part of the grid is frozen, which is related to soft selection.
The darker the selected area is, the stronger the application effect is.
In the brush setting, the strength of the brush is the strength of the brush in the painting process.
The higher the number, the stronger the selection area effect.
On the other hand, the lower the strength, the softer the application effect.
The size is the size of the area selected by the brush.
The focus is on the center of the brush.
The center of the brush is completely applied.
The size of the area is not reduced.
When the focus value is high, the reduction area is very small.
Most of them are completely applied to the set strength value.
The smaller the focus value, the more the reduction part.
It should be noted that the selection grid brush function is not able to move or rotate the grid.
So its function is to select the grid and then use the right keys.
Now let's take a look at the selection grid comparison function.
Use the selection grid comparison function.
In the 3D window, hold down the left mouse button and drag the mouse to select the grid that needs to be modified.
The selected area will be highlighted in green and will be highlighted in the same way in the 2D and 3D windows.
Similarly, we can use this tool to select the grid top in the 2D window.
Click on the 2D or 3D background to cancel the selection grid.
Click on the grid top to select only one grid top.
Click on the grid top on the line to select the entire line.
Double-click on the grid in the version and select the grid top of the entire version.
When choosing a section, if you select another section directly, the selection will be cancelled.
If we need to select several grid top of the area at the same time,
then we need to hold down the CTRL and SHIFT keys to stop selecting and then select all the grid top.
The grid top that needs to be selected is selected.
If you only press Shift and continue to select the grid, then the selected grid will be canceled, and the unselected grid will be selected.
If you only press Ctrl and continue to select, then the selected grid will be canceled.
After selecting, click on the selected grid.
You can move or rotate the selected area by positioning the ball.
Note that the center of rotation is where you click when selecting the grid.
After adjusting the grid position, turn on the simulation.
The board will reset the simulation and return to the correct simulation position.
When using the Select Grid Comparison or Select Grid Search function,
right-click on the grid in the selected area.
There is an option to rotate the grid level.
After selecting this option, the selected grid will automatically rotate the level.
If you select the grid,
the grid will rotate vertically,
and the grid will rotate vertically.
These functions are used to quickly adjust the grid position.
Grid rotation is mainly used to deal with the problem of grid surface damage or the back of the grid.
Here we will learn about the deep-layer fixing pin.
If the selected grid area is converted into a fixing pin,
then after we open the simulation,
this area will not return to its original position.
They will be fixed in the 3D space.
Right-click on the fixing pin area,
we can delete the extra fixing pins.
We will talk about the other functions in other tutorial videos.
There is not much to talk about here.
Finally, I will briefly introduce the Select Grid Comparison function.
The difference between this tool and the Select Grid Comparison tool is only in the method of selecting the grid.
The Select Grid Comparison tool is to use a mouse to draw a locking area,
and then select the grid peak in the area.
Now let's see how to use the Select Grid tool to deal with the problem of hand insertion.
In the process of using the Select Grid tool to select the grid peak and adjust it,
we can only select the grid that can be seen in the current view.
If the grid in the area is blocked by other objects in the 3D space,
such as a virtual model,
or by other panels,
or in a position that cannot be seen in our view,
then there is no way to be selected at the same time.
Therefore, in the process of selection,
we can select the grid in the 3D space first,
and then refer to the position of the green height.
In the 2D window, select the grid that needs to be modified in the frame,
and then move it back to the 3D window.
This can avoid the problem of the invisible grid being unable to be selected.
Next, we will repeat the previous operation.
After selecting the grid in the 2D window,
go back to the 3D window, use the positioning ball,
and pull these grid out a little,
so that they do not intersect with the hand.
Then there are some repeated operations.
We can adjust them in large pieces first,
and then adjust them in small parts.
Then turn on the simulation,
wait for the panel to slowly simulate the original position.
After the simulation is complete,
we will continue to select the grid in the 2D window,
and then move them to the 3D space.
Next, let's take a look at how to adjust the other side.
On the other side, the entire sleeve panel is outside.
What we have to do is to lift the sleeve up first,
so that the sleeve panel can be aligned with the position of the wrist.
When the sleeve panel is almost aligned with the position of the wrist,
we will pause the simulation,
and then we will start to select the grid.
Here it is still the same,
we select it in the 3D space,
and then in the 2D space,
use the position of the height just now as a reference to select the grid,
and then go back to the 3D space,
let the grid pass through the wrist,
and pull out some of the other holes.
Then press the control button to start the simulation,
and wait for the simulation to stabilize.
If there are still some gaps,
then continue to repeat the previous operation.
Finally, if the positioning ball you use is different from the coordinate system used in my video,
it may be that you used a default screen coordinate.
Right-click in the 3D background,
select the positioning ball,
you can select the world coordinate,
so it's the same as me,
it's based on the world as a coordinate.
Because the default screen coordinate is based on the camera,
so it's based on the 3D view.
See you next time.
Bye bye.